export const chapter = "Chapter - 5: Conservation of Plants and Animals ";
export const noOfActivities = 3;

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 1) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Tick the correct option:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question: "Why are forests important for living organisms on Earth?",
          optionA: "To provide clean air",
          optionB: "To regulate climate",
          optionC: "All of the above",
          correctAnswer: "C) All of the above",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the primary cause of deforestation due to human activities?",
          optionA: "Forest fires",
          optionB: "Industrialization",
          optionC: "Drought",
          correctAnswer: "B) Industrialization",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is the consequence of deforestation related to water absorption during heavy rainfall?",
          optionA: "Decreased rainfall",
          optionB: "Increased flooding in lower areas",
          optionC: "Formation of deserts",
          correctAnswer: "B) Increased flooding in lower areas",
        },
        {
          question: "Which factor contributes to the loss of biodiversity?",
          optionA: "Monoculture",
          optionB: "Conservation efforts",
          optionC: "Reforestation",
          correctAnswer: "A) Monoculture",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Why are migratory species important in maintaining biodiversity?",
          optionA: "They contribute to pollution control",
          optionB: "They help in maintaining genetic diversity",
          optionC: "They are immune to diseases",
          correctAnswer: "B) They help in maintaining genetic diversity",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the main objective of Wildlife Sanctuaries?",
          optionA: "Allowing hunting for specific species",
          optionB: "Protecting natural habitats of organisms",
          optionC: "Promoting human interference in ecosystems",
          correctAnswer: "B) Protecting natural habitats of organisms",
        },
        {
          question:
            "How does the loss of biodiversity impact the livelihood of people?",
          optionA: "Enhances economic growth",
          optionB: "Leads to economic loss for an industry or country",
          optionC: "Promotes sustainable development",
          correctAnswer: "B) Leads to economic loss for an industry or country",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Which project aims to protect the tiger population in India?",
          optionA: "Project Elephant",
          optionB: "Project Rhino",
          optionC: "Project Tiger",
          correctAnswer: "C) Project Tiger",
        },
        {
          question: "What is the main objective of reforestation?",
          optionA: "To destroy existing forests",
          optionB: "To create concrete jungles",
          optionC: "To plant trees and recreate destroyed forests",
          correctAnswer: "C) To plant trees and recreate destroyed forests",
        },
        {
          question:
            "What is one benefit of recycling paper mentioned in the text?",
          optionA: "Increased deforestation",
          optionB: "Energy and water conservation",
          optionC: "Enhanced newspaper production",
          correctAnswer: "B) Energy and water conservation",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 2) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Fill in the blanks:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Forests are essential for the existence and well-being of living organisms on Earth. One crucial function of forests is providing ________ for various plant and animal species.",
          optionA: "Shelter",
          optionB: "Food",
          optionC: "Water",
          correctAnswer: "a) Shelter",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Deforestation refers to the act of massive cutting down of trees and clearing of forests for other purposes. Forest fires, caused by lightning or human negligence, can burn thousands of square kilometers of forest, leading to ___________.",
          optionA: "Desertification",
          optionB: "Soil erosion",
          optionC: "Deforestation",
          correctAnswer: "c) Deforestation",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Acid rain, resulting from the combination of poisonous gases with rain, contributes to the destruction of trees and wildlife, causing __________.",
          optionA: "Desertification",
          optionB: "Deforestation",
          optionC: "Soil erosion",
          correctAnswer: "b) Deforestation",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Human activities such as clearing forests for settlements and cultivation contribute to the overgrazing and vanishing of ________.",
          optionA: "Deserts",
          optionB: "Grasslands",
          optionC: "Mountains",
          correctAnswer: "b) Grasslands",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Biodiversity, also known as biological diversity, refers to the diverse variety of plants, animals, and microorganisms on our planet. The variety of living organisms is collectively called ________.",
          optionA: "Biodiversity",
          optionB: "Species",
          optionC: "Flora",
          correctAnswer: "a) Biodiversity",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Species that resemble one another and are able to breed among themselves are called ________.",
          optionA: "Endemic species",
          optionB: "Migratory species",
          optionC: "Flora",
          correctAnswer: "b) Migratory species",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Monoculture, the practice of planting one type of plants in an area, leads to the loss of biodiversity by replacing natural forests rich in diversity. The endangered species affected include many varieties of ________.",
          optionA: "Deer",
          optionB: "Lions",
          optionC: "Elephants",
          correctAnswer: "a) Deer",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Wildlife sanctuaries are areas where wildlife is protected, and hunting and poaching are prohibited. These sanctuaries provide protection to wild animals by not disturbing their ________.",
          optionA: "Shelter",
          optionB: "Natural habitat",
          optionC: "Food source",
          correctAnswer: "b) Natural habitat",
        },
        {
          question:
            "National parks, pieces of land protected by the government to conserve wildlife, allow visitors to travel only within a limited area. Animals in national parks can move freely without the danger of ________.",
          optionA: "Forest fires",
          optionB: "Human interference",
          optionC: "Acid rain",
          correctAnswer: "b) Human interference",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Efforts to conserve forests and wildlife include reforestation, which involves planting trees to recreate forests. Reforestation aims to save trees and convert cities from concrete jungles to ________.",
          optionA: "Desert",
          optionB: "Green cities",
          optionC: "Grasslands",
          correctAnswer: "b) Green cities",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

if (localStorage.getItem("activityNumber") == 3) {
  activityData = {
    activity: "Write 'True' for True and 'False' for False statements:",
    questions: [
      [
        {
          question:
            "Forests play a minimal role in regulating the climate of a region.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Deforestation can lead to an increase in the level of oxygen in the atmosphere.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Biodiversity refers to the uniformity of living organisms in a particular area.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Monoculture, the planting of a single type of plant in an area, enhances biodiversity.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Wildlife sanctuaries allow unrestricted hunting and poaching of protected species.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Drought is a natural disaster responsible for the destruction of forests.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Species that resemble one another and can breed are called migratory species.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "Reforestation involves the removal of trees to create barren land.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question:
            "National parks allow unrestricted human interference in wildlife habitats.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "False",
        },
        {
          question: "Acid rain is a threat to wildlife and forests.",
          optionA: "True",
          optionB: "False",
          correctAnswer: "True",
        },
      ],
    ],
  };
}

export var activityData;
